Guide to the Margaret Fishback Papers, 1863-1978 and undated RL.00397
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Advertising Series, 1926-1974 and undated, 10 boxes
  - Client Files Subseries, 1931-1973 and undated
    - Travelers Insurance Co., 1958-1959 (Items removed to Oversize Materials, box OV10) (Box 35)
    - Trencher Furs, 1949-1950 (Box 39)
    - Tussy, 1958 and undated (Box 35)
    - Volkswagen, 1961 (Box 39)
    - Wallachs, 1960-1973 (Box 35)
    - West End Brewing, 1960 (Box 39)
    - Wrigley, 1954 and undated (Items removed to Oversize Materials, box OV12) (Box 35)
    - Assorted clients, 1957-1960 and undated (Box 35)
      Advertising work comprising a single item or few items per client. Clients include Bristol-Myers, Goodyear, Kaiser Foil, Lipton, Listerine, St. Mary's blankets, Statler Hotels, Topton Rug Manufacturing Company, and Your Personal Chef.
  - Conferences and Professional Societies Subseries, 1931-1974
    This subseries contains materials relating to Fishback's affiliations with various professional societies, as well as materials generated or collected for speaking engagements on advertising topics at other conferences.
    - Advertising Women of New York (AWNY), 1962-1974, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Advertising Women of New York (AWNY), 1966 (Box 36)
    - American Gas Association, 1965, 5 folders (Box 36)
      Includes materials from the 1965 convention of the American Gas Association in Miami Beach, Florida. Fishback was invited to the conference to deliver a speech, Whose Side Am I On? (the speech and speech preparation materials are located in the Speeches Subseries of the Writings Series). The American Gas Association contacted her to deliver this speech after hearing the speech at the 3rd Annual Consumer Conference, which was hosted by the Advertising Women of New York (AWNY) earlier that year.
    - Other Materials, 1931-1963 (Box 36)
      This folder contains a Fishback article that was reprinted in a convention program of the Advertising Club (1931); a letter regarding New York City's Tribute Dinner to Career Women, at which Fishback was the Guest of Honor; a 1954 issue of Independent Woman, the magazine of the National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Inc.; a letter from Associated Writers and Producers; and correspondence with the Zonta Club of New York.
  - Other Advertising Files Subseries, 1926-1971 and undated
    This subseries contains materials related to the advertising agencies for which Fishback worked, general advertising correspondence, assorted advertising writings by other authors, and other materials pertaining to Fishback's advertising career.
    - Advertising Agencies, 1941-1961
      Includes correspondence, some internal publications, and other administrative files relating to Fishback's work for advertising agencies. Materials related to specific advertising campaigns are located in the Client Files Subseries.
      - Cecil & Presbrey, 1941-1958 and undated (Box 36)
      - Doyle Dane Bernbach, 1959-1961 and undated (Box 36)
      - Warwick & Legler, 1951-1958 (Box 36)
      - Young & Rubicam, 1951-1959 (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1972, Arranged chronologically.
      Includes correspondence pertaining to Fishback's advertising career, but unassociated with any particular agencies or clients. Correspondence related to specific advertising agencies is located in the Advertising Agencies Subseries; correspondence related to specific advertising campaigns or clients is located in the Client Files Subseries.
      - 1920-1972, 6 folders (Box 37)
    - Trade Literature, 1941-1963
      Contains books by other authors on the subject of advertising. One book, Don Herold's Humor in Advertising, contains a contribution by Fishback. Some titles are signed by the authors.
      - 100 Greatest Advertisements: Who Wrote Them and What they Did, 1949 (Box 37)
      - 100 Greatest Advertisements: Who Wrote Them and What they Did, 2nd revised edition, 1959 (Box 37)
      - Confessions of an Advertising Man, 1963 (Box 37)
      - How to Get a Job and Win Success in Advertising, 1941 (Box 37)
      - Humor in Advertising and How to Make it Pay, 1962-1963, 2 folders (Box 38)
        Fishback contributed to this compilation of humorous advertisements and writings about humor in advertising. The book is inscribed to Fishback from author Don Herold. A second folder contains book preparation materials. These materials comprise correspondence between Fishback and Herold, as well as Photostat copies of Macy's advertisements.
      - Television Commercial, 1954 (Box 38)
    - Other Materials, 1926-1971
      Other advertising-related materials collected by Fishback.
      - 1960 Outdoor Annual, Outdoor Advertising Incorporated, 1960 (Box 38)
      - Brochures, 1926-1941 (Box 38)
      - Bureau of Advertising, An Experiment in Creativity, 1964-1965 (Box 38)
      - Clippings, 1954-1971 and undated (1 item removed to Oversize Materials, box OV12) (Box 38)
      - Coca-Cola idea, 1950 (Box 38)
        Includes correspondence between Fishback and the Coca-Cola Company regarding an advertisement idea Fishback submitted to the company. A Photostat of the proposed advertisement is also included.
      - [Heinz Ketchup proofs for Jewish-American publications, 1963, removed to Oversize Materials, box OV10] (Box 38)
      - Notes and ideas, 1943-1966 and undated (Box 38)
      - Press releases, 1945-1951 and undated (Box 38)
      - Some Headline 'Don'ts' and 'Do's,' undated (Box 38)
      - Writings by Fishback about advertising, 1932-1958 and undated (Box 38)
- Oversize Materials, 12 boxes
  Due to limitations of physical storage, box numbers of oversize materials do not necessarily run in sequence.
  - Personal Files Series, 1863-1978 and undated
    - Biographical Data Subseries, 1931-1949 (Box OV1)
    - Correspondence Subseries, 1918-1960 (Box OV2)
    - Other Papers Subseries
      - Clippings
        - Portland Press Herald Victory Edition, 15 August 1945 (Box OV1)
        - W. Somerset Maugham poem, Looking Back Part II, Show, 1962 (Box OV2)
      - Organizational Chart: Heaven, undated (Box OV2)
      - Papa Gander, publication of Woman's Home Companion, 1937 (Box OV2)
  - Writings Series, 1926-1978 and undated
    - General Files Subseries
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1955-1972 (Box OV2)
        - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box OV3)
    - Poetry Subseries, 1926-1978 and undated
      - Compilations, 1931-1968 and undated
        - Poems Made Up to Take Out, 1943-1963 and undated
          - Poems, Not in McKay book (Box OV2)
          - Proof and illustrations, undated (Box OV4)
      - Individual Poems, 1926-1978 and undated
        - Drafts, 1926-1974 and undated
          - Cape Cod Compass project, 1964-1965 (Box OV3)
          - Dream Men of Fair Women collection galley proof, Stage, 1936 (Box OV2)
        - Published works, 1926-1978 and undated
          - Illustrations for unnamed Woman's Day spread, circa 1962 (Box OV1)
          - King Features Syndicate proofs for Sunday Pictorial Review covers, 1952 (Box OV2)
          - Saturday Evening Post tear sheets, 1939-1940 (Box OV2)
          - Stalin's Happiest Subjects, This Week Magazine, 1949 (Box OV2)
          - Things my Mother Never Told Me, New York Times, supplement, A Better World through Electronics (advertisement), 1962 (Box OV2)
          - Underprivileged, Look, 1966 (Box OV2)
          - Assorted, 1930-1950 and undated (Box OV2)
    - Prose Subseries, 1928-1970 and undated
      - Articles, 1928-1965 and undated
        - Drafts, 1928-1965 and undated
          - Beware the Ides of March galley proof, Mademoiselle, 1940 and undated (Box OV2)
        - Published works, 1927-1959 and undated (Box OV1-OV3)
      - Books, 1935-1969 and undated
        - Safe Conduct: When to Behave--And Why, 1938-1958
          - Illustrations, undated (Box OV1)
          - Proof, 1938 (Box OV3)
  - Advertising Series, 1926-1974 and undated
    - Macy's Subseries, 1927-1970 and undated
      - Advertisements, 1927-1967 and undated
        - Scrapbook, 1929-1930 (Box OV5)
        - Divisional Advertisements, 1927-1933 and undated
          - Blankets, towels, bedspreads, 1931 and undated (Box OV6)
          - Costume Jewelry Department, undated (Box OV7)
          - Furniture, undated (Box OV6)
          - Gloves, undated (Box OV7)
          - Good Foods/Groceries, 1932-1933 and undated (Box OV6)
          - Housewares, undated (Box OV6)
          - Infants' and Children's Departments, 1930-1932 and undated (Box OV6)
          - Lingerie Department, undated (Box OV6)
          - Luggage, 1927 and undated (Box OV6)
          - Maids' uniforms, undated (Box OV6)
          - Men's department, undated (Box OV6)
          - Needlecraft and Notions Departments, 1932 and undated (Box OV6)
          - Personal Shopping Service, undated (Box OV6)
          - Place de l'opera, 1933 (Box OV7)
          - Wine and Liquor Store, undated (Box OV6)
        - Institutional Advertisements (General), 1927-1967 and undated
          - Photostat proofs, 1928-1939 and undated (Box OV7)
          - Proofs, 1927-1941 and undated (Box OV7-OV9)
          - Sketches for illustrations, 1943 and undated (Box OV9)
          - Sketches for illustrations, 1947 and undated (Box OV8)
          - Tear sheets, 1932-1948 (Box OV8)
          - Who's Who in Toyland booklet, undated (Box OV9)
        - Institutional Advertisements (Topical), 1930-1967 and undated
          - Christmas, 1930-1964 and undated (Box OV8)
          - Diamonds, 1961-1967 (Box OV8)
          - Macy's Barnyard, undated (Box OV8)
          - Macy's Information Clerk, undated (Box OV8)
          - Thanksgiving Parade, 1942-1946 and undated (Box OV8)
      - Correspondence, general, 1928-1966 and undated (Box OV9)
      - Jack Strauss poem and David Yunich Christmas speech, 1961-1966 (Box OV9)
      - Sheet music, To Thee, O Macy's Proud and Strong, undated 1961-1966 (Box OV9)
    - Client Files Subseries, 1931-1973 and undated
      - Arrow, 1958-1959 and undated (Box OV10)
      - Ballantine Beer, undated (Box OV11)
      - Barton's Candy Corporation, 1960-1964 and undated (Box OV11)
      - Better Vision Institute, 1948-1955 and undated (Box OV11)
      - Borden's, 1958-1959 (Box OV11)
      - Brooklyn Museum Industrial Design Division, undated (Box OV11)
      - Chef Boy-Ar-Dee, 1959 (Box OV11)
      - Clairol, 1964-1965 and undated (Box OV11)
      - DeSoto cars, 1940 and undated (Box OV12)
      - Gimbels, 1969 and undated (Box OV10)
      - Great Atlantic & Pacific Tea Company (A&P), 1931-1959 and undated (Box OV10)
      - Kellogg's, 1941 (Box OV10)
      - Loft's Candy, 1957 (Box OV4)
      - Martex (The Magic Towel), 1961-1962 (Box OV10)
      - National Safety Council, 1947 and undated (Box OV12)
      - Nazareth, 1949-1950 (Box OV10)
      - Nemo, undated (Box OV10)
      - Norcross, 1958-1960 (Box OV12)
      - Simmons Beautyrest, 1959 (Box OV12)
      - Travelers Insurance Co., 1958-1959 (Box OV10)
      - Wrigley, 1954 and undated (Box OV12)
    - Other Advertising Files Subseries, 1926-1971 and undated
      - Other Materials, 1926-1971 and undated
        - Clippings, 1954-1971 and undated (Box OV12)
        - Heinz Ketchup proofs for Jewish-American publications, 1963 (Box OV10)